Register of the Richard C. Cornuelle papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard C. Cornuelle papers
1895-2011
2015C13
Hoover Institution Archives
33 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box (14.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, notes, printed matter, photographs, and videocassettes relating to libertarian social theory and to private philanthropy as a means of meeting social needs.
Cornuelle, Richard C., 1927-2011.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection(s)
Milton Friedman papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
Richard Charles Cornuelle was a well-known American libertarian thinker who is credited with coining the term “independent sector.” He is the author of a number of articles and books, among them his seminal work, Reclaiming the American Dream (1965).
1927 April 10 Born in Elwood, Indiana, the second son of Herbert Cumming Cornuelle and Gertrude Schleitzer Cornuelle.
1928 April Moved with his family to Hartford City, Indiana, where his father was pastor of the Hartford City Presbyterian Church.
1934 September - 1937 June Attended North Ward Elementary School in Hartford City, completing grades 1 through 3 there.
1936 April 21 His father died of lobar pneumonia after a brief illness.
1937 June Drove to California with family to start a new life in Los Angeles.
1937 September - 1939 June Attended grades 4 to 6 at Aldema Elementary School in Highland Park, Los Angeles, California.
1939 September - 1940 June Attended grades 7 and 8 at Luther Burbank Junior High School in Highland Park.
1940 Summer Moved to Pasadena, California.
1940 September - 1942 June Attended grades 9 and 10 at McKinley Junior High School in Pasadena, California
1942 September - 1944 June Attended grades 11 and 12 to complete high school at Pasadena Junior College.
1944 April 10 Enlisted in the United States Naval Reserve as an Apprentice Seaman. While in the Navy he attended Occidental College as a pre-med student.
1945 February Discharged from the Navy.
1948 June Graduated from Occidental College with a major in economics.
1948 September - 1950 June Attended New York University's Graduate School of Business Administration to study under Ludwig Von Mises. Worked for the National Industrial Conference Board.
1950 July - 1952 Worked for the Foundation for Economic Education and the Small Business Economic Foundation in Evanston, Illinois.
1952 Worked for the William Volker Fund in San Mateo, California.
1954 November 10 Married Sydney Walton in San Francisco, California.
1955 November 7 Daughter, Suzanne Cornuelle was born in San Francisco.
1957 Moved to Princeton, New Jersey to work for the Princeton Panel.
1958 February 1 Son, Peter Garrett was born in San Francisco.
1959 February 28 Daughter, Jenny Cornuelle was born in San Francisco.
1958-1966 Returned to the William Volker Fund and worked with related organizations.
1965 Book, Reclaiming the American Dream, was published.
1966-1969 Relocated to New York City as executive vice president of the National Association of Manufacturers.
1967 Was separated from Sydney Cornuelle and later divorced.
1970 Became a business consultant and full-time writer.
1975 Book, De-Managing America, was published.
1983 Book, Healing America, was published.
1991 February 22 Married Elizabeth Kaplan Fonseca in New York.
2011 April 26 Died
As written by Richard Cornuelle (Source): Folder 1 and 5, Richard C. Cornuelle papers, 1915-2011, Box 1, Hoover Institution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection documents the personal and professional life of Richard Charles Cornuelle. Materials in the collection include biographical and genealogical documents, correspondence, and various projects with which Cornuelle was involved, mainly from the Earhart Foundation and the J. M. Kaplan Fund or as an independent contributor. The collection also includes research files on various topics of interest to Cornuelle, some of which include: business, education, the independent sector, labor and workforce, and violence in United States.
Additionally housed are speeches and writings of Cornuelle and other individuals. Cornuelle's writings include numerous articles, papers, an unpublished manuscript entitled "Garet Garrett’s Journal," as well as his published books: Reclaiming the American Dream (1965), De-Managing America: The Final Revolution (1975), and Healing America (1983). There are also articles written by Cornuelle that were featured in the Times Literary Supplement.
The symposiums and conferences section of the collection is comprised of files pertaining to events such as conferences, roundtables, and workshops attended by Cornuelle. The collection also contains a printed matter file, which includes various publications, journals, magazines, and annual reports collected by Cornuelle. Sound and video recordings include a compact sound cassette recording and various video recordings. Of special note is a VHS tape entitled “A Conversation with Richard Cornuelle,” created by the Liberty Fund, Intellectual Portrait Series.
When possible the original folder titles and arrangement established by Richard Cornuelle have been retained.
Libertarianism--United States.; United States--Economic policy.; Charities--United States.; Associations, institutions, etc.--United States.; Video tapes.
- Biographical File, 1927-2011
  Scope and Contents
  The biographical file documents the personal and family life of Richard Cornuelle and is composed of biographical and genealogical information on Cornuelle and some of his family members. Additional files concern hobbies and interests, school and family photos, certificates and diplomas, and school yearbooks.
  - Biographical data, 1927-1991 (Text 1: 1)
  - Certificates and diplomas, 1943-1948 (Text 1: 2)
  - Cornuelle, Herbert (brother), 1996 (Text 1: 3)
  - Cornuelle, Ralph (brother), 2000 (Text 1: 4)
  - Geneaology file, 1936-2002
    Comprised of biographical outlines of family members, clippings, copies of photos that were used in the family scrapbook, correspondence,research done as part of a family genealogy project, writings, and sections of the family tree.
    - Biographical outlines of family members, circa 1996 (Text 1: 5)
    - Clippings, 1936, 1994 (Text 1: 6)
    - Copies of photos for scrapbook, circa 1996 (Text 1: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1995-2002 (Text 1: 8)
    - Family tree, circa 1990s (Text 1: 9)
    - Research, circa 1996 (Text 1: 10)
    - Writings, circa 1996 (Text 1: 11)
  - Hobbies and interests, 1999-2011
    Composed of materials that reflect the extracurricular interests of Cornuelle. Includes information on museums, opera, and ballet, as well as walking/hiking and tennis.
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 2007 (Text 1: 12)
    - The Metropolitan Opera, 2006-2011 (Text 1: 13)
    - The Museum of Modern Art, 2008 (Text 1: 14)
    - New York City Ballet, 2005-2009 (Text 1: 15)
    - Tennis, 2009 (Text 1: 16)
    - Walking, 1999-2006 (Text 1: 17)
    - York House, Inc., circa 2000s (Text 1: 18)
  - Interview with Richard Cornuelle, undated (Text 1: 19)
  - Photographs, 1929-1993
    - Childhood, 1929, 1939 (Text 1: 20)
    - Formative years, 1943-1949 (Text 1: 21)
    - Publicity photos, 1970-1993 (Text 2: 1)
    - Unidentified, undated (Text 2: 2)
  - Trips file, 1990-2002
    Includes pamphlets, performance programs, currency, notes, brochures, and a transparency of a Russian religious icon.
    - British Isles, circa 1990 (Text 2: 3)
    - Italy, circa 1990 (Text 2: 4)
    - Russia, 1997 (Text 2: 5)
    - Spain, 1999-2002 (Text 2: 6)
    - United States and Latin America, 1990 (Text 2: 7)
  - Yearbooks, 1939-1948
    Comprised of copies of yearbooks from schools attended by Cornuelle. File also includes a play bill from the Occidental College Glee Clubs Home Concert.
    - Luther Burbank Junior High School, 1939-1941 (Text 2: 8)
    - Pasadena Junior College, 1944 (Text 2: 9)
    - Occidental College, 1945 (Text 2: 10)
    - Occidental College, 1947 (Text 2: 11)
    - Occidental College, 1948 (Text 3: 1)
    - Occidental College Glee Clubs: Home Concert, 1948 (Text 3: 2)
- Correspondence, 1957-2010
  Composed of correspondence between Richard Cornuelle and his friends, family, and associates. Materials have been filed by the last name; when the last name is unknown, materials are filed by the first name. The file titles are a repeat of original file titles created by Cornuelle. The correspondence is of both a personal and professional nature.
  - Alexander, Gary, 1993 (Text 3: 3)
  - Aligica, Paul, 2004-2005 (Text 3: 4)
  - Amis, Martin, 1996 (Text 3: 5)
  - Aramony, William, 1977-1996 (Text 3: 6)
  - Arturo, undated (Text 3: 7)
  - Ashby, Thaddeus, 1976 (Text 3: 8)
  - Austin, undated (Text 3: 9)
  - Barber, Arthur, 1977 (Text 3: 10)
  - Barnett, Louis, 2009 (Text 3: 11)
  - Bauer, Peter, 1992 (Text 3: 12)
  - Bemis, Gregg, 1975 (Text 3: 13)
  - Birdie, 1997 (Text 3: 14)
  - Boaz, David D., 1993 (Text 3: 15)
  - Boettke, Peter J., 2004-2006 (Text 3: 16)
  - Borders, William, 1981 (Text 3: 17)
  - Bray, Charles W., 1996 (Text 3: 18)
  - Brin, David, 2004-2008 (Text 3: 19)
  - Carl, 2004 (Text 3: 20)
  - Chamberlain, John, 1993 (Text 3: 21)
  - Charney, Melvin, 1998 (Text 3: 22)
  - Churchill, John (Phi Beta Kappa Society), 2004 (Text 3: 23)
  - Ciepley, David, 2005 (Text 3: 24)
  - Cody, John V., 1984 (Text 3: 25)
  - Cohen, Stanley, 1976 (Text 3: 26)
  - Corrigan, Chris, 2005 (Text 3: 27)
  - Cornuelle, Herbert, circa 1970 (Text 3: 28)
  - Cuito, Amadeo, 1984-1995 (Text 3: 29)
  - David, 1992-1995 (Text 3: 30)
  - Davidson, John Matthew, 1995 (Text 3: 31)
  - Dennis, Kimberly O., 1999 (Text 3: 32)
  - Dennis, William C., 2002-2006 (Text 3: 33)
  - Dewar, Tom, 2001 (Text 3: 34)
  - Ealy, Lenore, 2003-2006 (Text 3: 35)
  - Edna, 1992 (Text 3: 36)
  - Elaine, 2000 (Text 3: 37)
  - Ellinghaus, William H., 1975 (Text 3: 38)
  - Ene, 2004 (Text 3: 39)
  - Erickson, Donald A., 1994 (Text 3: 40)
  - Finch, Robert H., 1994 (Text 3: 41)
  - Flynn, William, 1987 (Text 3: 42)
  - Fonseca, Caio, 1995 (Text 3: 43)
  - Fonseca, Elizabeth K., 1989 (Text 3: 44)
  - Fonseca, Isabel, 2003 (Text 3: 45)
  - Fonseca, Quina, 1995 (Text 3: 46)
  - Ford, Jerry, 1976 (Text 3: 47)
  - Fountain, Steve, 1998 (Text 3: 48)
  - Frazer, Bruce W., 1998 (Text 3: 49)
  - Fred and Catherine, 1997 (Text 3: 50)
  - Friedman, Jeffrey, 2007 (Text 4: 1)
  - Fuhrman, Peter, 1994 (Text 4: 2)
  - Girard, Richard, 1994 (Text 4: 3)
  - Gonzalo, undated (Text 4: 4)
  - Gotcher, Robert and Sally, 1990 (Text 4: 5)
  - de Grazia, Sebastian, 1979 (Text 4: 6)
  - Green, Rose, 1981 (Text 4: 7)
  - Guare, John, circa 1990 (Text 4: 8)
  - von Hayek, Friedrich August, 1974-1975 (Text 4: 9)
  - Heilbroner, Robert, undated (Text 4: 10)
  - Helen, 1998 (Text 4: 11)
  - Helstrom, Carl, 1994 (Text 4: 12)
  - Herman, David, 1993 (Text 4: 13)
  - Hess, Karl, 1992 (Text 4: 14)
  - Hibbs, John, 1994 (Text 4: 15)
  - Hill, Robert, 1972 (Text 4: 16)
  - Hoffman, Everett, undated (Text 4: 17)
  - Howard, Helen, 1998-1999 (Text 4: 18)
  - Hunt, Hugh S., 1992 (Text 4: 19)
  - The Institute of Economic Affairs, 1993-2000 (Text 4: 20)
  - Jake, 1999 (Text 4: 21)
  - Jaworski, Joseph, 1981 (Text 4: 22)
  - Jeannie, 2004 (Text 4: 23)
  - Jim, undated (Text 4: 24)
  - Kaplan Choate/ Brandywine Trust, 1998 (Text 4: 25)
  - Karnick, S. T., 2005 (Text 4: 26)
  - Kathryn, undated (Text 4: 27)
  - Kekst, Gershon, 1979 (Text 4: 28)
  - Kempner, Maximilian W., 1976 (Text 4: 29)
  - Kinsey, Doug, 1973 (Text 4: 30)
  - Klein, Daniel, 1993 (Text 4: 31)
  - Koch, Charles G., 1993 (Text 4: 32)
  - Krusoe, Jim, 2000-2005 (Text 4: 33)
  - Lenkowsky, Les, 2001 (Text 4: 34)
  - Letters from cousins, 2001 (Text 4: 35)
  - Liggio, Leonard, 2004 (Text 4: 36)
  - Lohmann, Roger, 2003 (Text 4: 37)
  - MacBride, Roger Lee, 1994 (Text 4: 38)
  - Marvel, Isabel Jane, 2006 (Text 4: 39)
  - McCarthy, John, 1987 (Text 4: 40)
  - McClaughry, John, 1993 (Text 4: 41)
  - McKnight, John, 1999-2005 (Text 4: 42)
  - Meares, Charles W. V., 1981 (Text 4: 43)
  - Meltzer, Jay I., 1995 (Text 4: 44)
  - Meyer, Karl E., 1992 (Text 4: 45)
  - Miller, J. J., 2003 (Text 4: 46)
  - Montgomery, Harry, 1999-2001 (Text 4: 47)
  - Morgan, Claire, 2002-2009 (Text 4: 48)
  - Mount, Ferdinand, 1993 (Text 4: 49)
  - Murray, Charles, 1992, 1997 (Text 4: 50)
  - Nash, George H., 2002 (Text 4: 51)
  - Nat, 1996 (Text 4: 52)
  - Nettler, Gwynne, 1993 (Text 4: 53)
  - Nott, David, 2005 (Text 4: 54)
  - Oney, Steve, 1994 (Text 4: 55)
  - Pearson, George, 1993 (Text 4: 56)
  - Piereson, James, 1989-2000 (Text 4: 57)
  - The Princeton Panel, 1957 (Text 4: 58)
  - Prychit, David, 2003 (Text 4: 59)
  - Raimondo, Justin, 1993 (Text 4: 60)
  - Ramsey, Bruce, 2003-2006 (Text 4: 61)
  - Rand, Carole Ann, 1994 (Text 4: 62)
  - Ream, Roger, 2000 (Text 4: 63)
  - Recommendation letters, 1982-2001 (Text 4: 64)
  - Rich, Andrea Millen, 2006 (Text 4: 65)
  - Rieff, David, 1992 (Text 4: 66)
  - Sally, 2004 (Text 4: 67)
  - Samkova-Vesala, Klara, 1994 (Text 4: 68)
  - Scheerer, Idoline, 2006 (Text 4: 69)
  - Schutten, Suzanne, 2004 (Text 4: 70)
  - Simon, John, 1980 (Text 4: 71)
  - Smith, Ted J., III, 1994 (Text 4: 72)
  - Sommer, Jack, 2006 (Text 4: 73)
  - Soros, George, 1997 (Text 4: 74)
  - Strong, Michael, 2005-2006 (Text 4: 75)
  - Sturges, Benjamin R., 1992 (Text 4: 76)
  - Taylor, George, 1974 (Text 4: 77)
  - Templeton, Kenneth S., 1998-2000 (Text 4: 78)
  - Thomas, Michael, 1991 (Text 4: 79)
  - Unidentified, 1986-2010 (Text 4: 80)
  - Velmans, Jessica, 1991 (Text 4: 81)
  - Ware, Richard, 1992-2002 (Text 4: 82)
  - Welensky, Donna, 2009 (Text 4: 83)
  - Wooster, M. M., 2005 (Text 4: 84)
  - di Zerega, Gus, 2003-2009 (Text 4: 85)
- Projects File, 1968-2011
  Comprised of materials related to various projects Cornuelle was involved in, supported, or recommended for funding. Though materials are mainly from the Earhart Foundation and the J. M. Kaplan Fund, other projects include: Cato Institute, Edison Project, Gateway to the Future, Liberty Fund, and Underwriters Laboratories.
  - Cato Institute, 1993-2004 (Text 5: 1)
  - Earhart Foundation File, 1968-2011
    Composed of articles, clippings, correspondence, meeting minutes, documents regarding the history of the foundation, memoranda, notes, and an analysis paper entitled, “Where do we go from here? The Future of Free Societies: The first stage of analysis undertaken for the Earhart Foundation,” commissioned by the Earhart Foundation and written by Richard Cornuelle.
    - Articles, 1968-2011 (Text 5: 2)
    - Clippings, circa 1970 (Text 5: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2007 (Text 5: 4)
    - "The Death and Resurrection of Community in America,", undated (Text 5: 5)
    - Earhart Foundation, January 31st, 1998 Meeting (Text 5: 6)
    - Earhart Foundation, April 4th, 1998 Meeting (Text 5: 7)
    - Historical documents, 1990-1995 (Text 5: 8-9)
    - Memoranda, 1994-1999 (Text 6: 1)
    - Notes, 1990-1995 (Text 6: 2)
    - "Where do we go from here? The Future of Free Societies: The first stage of analysis undertaken for the Earhart Foundation,", circa 1990 (Text 6: 3)
  - The Edison Project, 1994-1996 (Text 6: 4)
  - Gateway to the Future, 2006-2007 (Text 6: 5)
  - J. M. Kaplan Fund File, 1995-2010
    Comprised of various files concerning initiatives and grants funded by the J. M. Kaplan Fund. Some of the organizations that benefitted include: Critical Review Foundation, DonorsTrust, Manhattan Institute for Policy Research, and School of Advanced International Studies at Johns Hopkins.
    - The Assetbased Community Development Institute, 1998-2002 (Text 6: 6)
    - Correspondence, 2005-2009 (Text 6: 7)
    - Critical Review Foundation, Inc., 2001-2007 (Text 6: 8)
    - DonorsTrust, 2004-2010 (Text 6: 9)
    - Financial records, 1995-2010 (Text 6: 10)
    - Grant awards and requests, 2000-2010 (Text 6: 11)
    - Kaplan Homestead blueprints, 1996 (Text 6: 12)
    - Manhattan Institute for Policy Research, 1998-2008 (Text 7: 1)
    - Memoranda, 2003, 2009 (Text 7: 2)
    - National Results Council, 2000-2001 (Text 7: 3)
    - New Inquiry Into Social Research, 1995-2009 (Text 7: 4)
    - School of Advanced International Studies: Johns Hopkins, 1996-1999 (Text 7: 5)
    - Social Security Reform, 1995-1996 (Text 7: 6)
  - Liberty Fund, 1994 (Text 7: 7)
  - Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., 1976-1978 (Text 7: 8)
- Research File, 1895-2011
  Composed of research materials gathered by Cornuelle on topics which he was interested in actively writing about. The majority of research materials gathered pertain to business, education, the environment, the independent sector, labor and workforce, and violence in the United States. Additional topics include baby boomers, photographic reproductions from the Bettman Archives, Jonas Salk, and documents pertaining to the concept of philanthropic enterprise. Original order of documents has been retained
  - Appendices, circa 1980s, 2004 (Text 8: 1)
  - Baby Boomers, 1995 (Text 8: 2)
  - Bettmann Archives reprints, 1916-1954 (Text 8: 3)
  - Business file, 1967-2003
    Includes information on contract management, cost accounting, industry standards, and spontaneous order materials.
    - Business Starts, Business Failures, Bankruptcy Cases - Number of National Nonprofit Associations, 1980-1997 (Text 8: 4)
    - Contract Management, 1967-1976 (Text 8: 5)
    - Center for the Study of Market Processes, 1993 (Text 8: 6)
    - "History of Cost Accounting,", 1996 (Text 8: 7)
    - Industry Standards, 1998 (Text 8: 8)
    - Spontaneous Order Materials, 1995-2003 (Text 8: 9-10)
  - Census of Governments, 1999 (Text 8: 11)
  - Copies of The New York Times, articles, circa 1915 (Text 8: 12)
  - Education, 1963-2008
    Includes information on early education in the U.S., homeschooling, higher education, and intelligence testing.
    - Early Education in the U.S., 1963-1970 (Text 8: 13)
    - "Education Vouchers: A Report on Financing Elementary Education by Grants to Parents,", 1970 (Text 8: 14)
    - Homeschooling, 1998-1999 (Text 9: 1)
    - "How Free Enterprise Is Solving the Problem of the Needy College Student,", 1964 (Text 9: 2)
    - National Assessment of Edcational Progress (writing reports), 1969-1979 (Text 9: 3)
    - "Origins and Development in Intelligence Testing,", 1988 (Text 9: 4)
    - Total Enrollment in Public and Private Schools, Both K-12 and Colleges, 1999-2008 (Text 9: 5)
  - Eligibility to vote/Registered to vote, 1986 (Text 9: 6)
  - Federal Reserve System - Jekyll Island Meeting, 1977 (Text 9: 7)
  - Gunda - The Mad Elephant, circa 1915 (Text 9: 8)
  - The Hawaiian Room, circa 1980 (Text 9: 9)
  - History of Good Samaritan Law and additional New York State material, 1988, 1998 (Text 9: 10)
  - History of Mid-Wives, 1986, 1998 (Text 9: 11)
  - Environmentalism, 1992-1996
    Includes a proposal from the Competitive Enterprise Institute and information regarding regulations for environmental management.
    - A Proposal of the Competitive Enterprise Institute, 1992 (Text 9: 12)
    - Voluntary Regulations for Environmental Management, 1996 (Text 9: 13)
  - The Freedom Train Story, 1985 (Text 9: 14)
  - Independent sector, 1974-1999
    Comprised of files pertaining to the independent sector, the Heartland Institute, and USA Funds.
    - The Heartland Institute, 1995-1996 (Text 9: 15)
    - Independent Sector, 1975-1995 (Text 9: 16)
    - Independent Sector, 1990-1995 (Text 9: 17)
    - USA Funds, 1974-1999 (Text 9: 18)
  - Interviews, 1997-2006 (Text 10: 1)
  - Jonas Salk, 2011 (Text 10: 2)
  - Labor and workforce, 1895-2000
    Includes information on the history of labor in the United States, manufacturing, and the workforce demographic.
    - History of Labor in the U.S., 1966 (Text 10: 3)
    - Labor, 1980 (Text 10: 4)
    - People Working as Free Agents as Opposed to Working for Wages, 1998 (Text 10: 5)
    - Pins, 1999 (Text 10: 6)
    - Street enterprise, 1992, 1996 (Text 10: 7)
    - Workforce, 1987-2000 (Text 10: 8)
  - Material on Edward Bellamy's "Looking Backward,", 1998 (Text 10: 9)
  - The National Information Bureau, 1981 (Text 10: 10)
  - Patent Office, 1997 (Text 10: 11)
  - The Philanthropic Enterprise, 1987-2002 (Text 10: 12)
  - Possible picks for "The Members of the Council,", 1895-1970 (Text 10: 13)
  - References, 1998-2000 (Text 10: 14)
  - "The Role and Application of Scientific and Technical Information in the Process of Innovation: Invention and Conception,", 1975 (Text 11: 1)
  - Southern New England Telephone Company Corporate Identification Program, 1982 (Text 11: 2)
  - "Serfdom in Early America,", 1985, 1987 (Text 11: 3)
  - Statistics, circa 1992 (Text 11: 4)
  - Steerage and conscription in Germany, 1999 (Text 11: 5)
  - Thomas Jefferson, "On the State of Virginia,", 1998 (Text 11: 6)
  - Violence, 1984-1998
    Comprised of documents pertaining to violence in the U.S. and two files regarding the Leo Frank case.
    - "Big Trouble: Murder in a Small Western Town Sets Off a Struggle for the Soul of America,", circa 1994 (Text 11: 7)
    - Leo Frank, 1984-1998 (Text 11: 8-9)
    - Violence in U.S., circa 1990 (Text 11: 10)
  - Washington, 1983 (Text 11: 11)
- Speeches and Writings, 1950-2011
  Composed of speeches and writings of various individuals, including Richard Cornuelle.
  - Adelman, Carol, 2000 (Text 11: 12)
  - Adkins, Cindy, 2008 (Text 11: 13)
  - Agre, Philip E., 1998 (Text 11: 14)
  - Alexander, Gerard, 2007 (Text 11: 15)
  - Aligica, Paul Dragos, 2005 (Text 11: 16)
  - Allen, Charlotte, 2009 (Text 11: 17)
  - Anderson, Kenneth, 1996-1998 (Text 12: 1)
  - Apter, David E., undated (Text 12: 2)
  - Aramony, William, 1990-1992 (Text 12: 3)
  - Aristides, undated (Text 12: 4)
  - Baetjer, Howard, 2007 (Text 12: 5)
  - Boida, Peter, undated (Text 12: 6)
  - Bailey, Ronald, 2006-2007 (Text 12: 7)
  - Barger, Harold and Gwyneth, 1981 (Text 12: 8)
  - Barody, William J., Jr., 1978 (Text 12: 9)
  - Barringer, Felicity, 2005 (Text 12: 10)
  - Barry, Norman, 1982 (Text 12: 11)
  - Bayles, Martha and McClay, Wilfred M., 2001 (Text 12: 12)
  - Beaulier, Scott A., circa 2000 (Text 12: 13)
  - Beito, David T., circa 2000 (Text 12: 14)
  - Bell, Daniel, circa 2000 (Text 12: 15)
  - Bellow, Saul, 2000 (Text 12: 16)
  - Benkler, Yochai, 2002-2004 (Text 12: 17)
  - de Benoist, Alain, circa 2000s (Text 12: 18)
  - Berkowitz, Peter, 2007 (Text 12: 19)
  - Bernstein, Ilya, circa 2000s (Text 12: 20)
  - Bernstein, Paul, circa 1990s (Text 12: 21)
  - Biegler, John C., 1975 (Text 12: 22)
  - Black, Anthony, 2002 (Text 13: 1)
  - Blaustein, Arthur I., 2003 (Text 13: 2)
  - Bluhdorn, Charles G., 1976 (Text 13: 3)
  - Boaz, David, 2006 (Text 13: 4)
  - Boettke, Peter, circa 2000s (Text 13: 5-6)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J., circa 1990s (Text 13: 7)
  - Borders, Max, circa 2000s (Text 13: 8)
  - Boschee, Jerr, circa 1990 (Text 13: 9)
  - Boswell, Christopher M., 2009 (Text 13: 10)
  - Botkin, Daniel B., 2009 (Text 13: 11)
  - Bragin, Michael, 1999 (Text 13: 12)
  - Brin, David, 2004-2008 (Text 13: 13)